NAJEE MOZIE

➤ NajeeMozie@gmail.com



(917) 532-7413



Queens, NY

EDUCATION

Queens College

Queens, NY (01/2024- current)

Bachelor of Science Computer Science

LaGuardia Community College

Long Island City, NY (09/2022- 12/2023)

Globe Institute of Technology

New York, NY (01/2008-08/2009)

Associate of Applied Science: Business

Management with Computer

Applications

Long Island City High School

Long Island City, NY (06/2006)

High School Diploma

CERTIFICATIONS

- CompTIA A+
- CompTIA Network+
- CompTIA Security+
- CCNA Cisco Certified Network Associate

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Hardworking and passionate IT professional with an 11-year background in system administration, hardware and software troubleshooting, network security, and network management for the federal government and private sector. Strong organizational, interpersonal, time management, and problem-solving skills.

EXPERIENCE

Lincoln IT - Junior Network Analyst New York (07/2021 - Current)

- Monitoring network performance, troubleshooting issues, and ensuring network availability and reliability.
- Designing, configuring, and optimizing network infrastructure, including routers, switches, firewalls, and other network devices.
- Creating and maintaining network documentation, including network diagrams, configurations, and procedures for future reference.
- Understanding and implementation of various routing protocols (BGP, OSPF, IS-IS, EIGRP, IGRP, RIP).

United States Army - Information Technology Specialist (09/2012 - 09/2024)

- Responsible for various IT and communication equipment for different military commands.
- Controlled and managed server room, wireless network, server infrastructure, audiovisual equipment, laptops, and video conferencing equipment.
- Performed daily system monitoring, verifying integrity and availability of hardware, server resources, systems, and key processes.
- Resolved escalated issues by serving as subject matter expert on wide-ranging IT issues.
- Attend regular meetings to report project progress and address issues.

New York Passport Agency - Passport Support Associate New York, NY (05/2017 - 01/2019)

- Worked closely with applicants to determine eligibility and verify the accuracy and integrity of application data.
- Updated operational records of licensing information using computer terminals.

SKILLS

- Leadership and Teamwork
- Communication
- Organizational
- Problem-solving
- Analytical Thinking
- Adaptability
- Attention to Detail
- Troubleshooting
- Network Configuration (OSPF, EIGRP, RIP)
- Security (Network security, encryption, incident response)
- System Administration
- Operating Systems (Windows & macOS)

- Assisted newly hired members in learning about application reviews and verification procedures, performance strategies, and customer service techniques.
- Meticulous attention to detail while consistently meeting deadlines.

Time Warner Cable - Field Technician

Queens, NY 01/2016 - 02/2017

- Analytical problem solving, installing residential video data and voice services.
- Maintenance and repair of residential coaxial, and phone wiring.
- Performing software configuration for customer's devices.
- Underground and aerial cable service installations and disconnections.

American Eagle - Stock Worker

New York, NY (01/2009 - 01/2012)

- Supported store operations by aiding in stocking, executing floor sets, and ensuring seamless opening and closing procedures.
- Recognized as a retail stock clerk with a reputation for delivering exceptional customer service and fostering a collaborative teamoriented approach.
- Welcomed and assisted customers while adeptly handling transactions in a bustling retail setting situated at the vibrant heart of Times Square in Manhattan, NY.
- Contributed to a location consistently ranked among the top performers nationwide for American Eagle, contributing to its status as one of the highest-grossing stores in the company.

VOLUNTEERING

Teach Computer Basics to Seniors

Sunnyside Community Services (09/2023 - 08/2024)

- Facilitating enhanced computer literacy by introducing Microsoft Suit and other Windows applications to seniors.
- Simply teaching internet navigation and security.
- Empowering seniors to be able to confidently use IT equipment independently.

Chess Club for kids

Queens Public Library - Woodside Branch (09/2023 - present)

- Inspire and engage elementary through high school students by teaching strategy and logic through the game of chess.
- Mentoring and promoting teamwork and sportsmanship to students.